James Simmons papers, 1945-1996
Emory University
- Writings by Simmons, circa 1962-1999, Series 3; Boxes 23-52, OP 1-4
  - Prose, Subseries 3.2; Boxes 31-43
    - "Collingwood's Theory of Art: Art is Language," TS (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - "Commercialism," TS (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - "The Confused Teacher Cannot Take His Work Seriously," TS (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - "Cruxes," TS (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - "Derry/Coleraine," TSS (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - "The Diction of Yeats," TSS (Box OP1)
    - "Dimishment by Labels," TS (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - "Discriminations," TS (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - "Dryden," MS (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - "Editorial: First Steps in Revolution," TS (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - "Education," TS (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - "The Enemy," MS (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - "English Poetry," TS (Box 31, Folder 31)
    - "Environment and Entertainment," TS (Box 31, Folder 32)
    - "Existentialism and Love," TS (Box 31, Folder 33)
    - "The Foreman's Estimates," TSS (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - "Forrest Reid-W.B. Yeats," MS (Box 31, Folder 35)
    - "Frank O'Connor on the Present Troubles," TS (Box 31, Folder 36)
    - "Freedom and Democracy," MS (Box 31, Folder 37)
    - "George Crabbe," MS (Box 31, Folder 38)
    - "George Formby," TS (Box 31, Folder 39)
    - "The Great Claims Made for Literature," TS (Box 31, Folder 40)
    - "Handbook for Revolutionaries," TS (Box 31, Folder 41)
    - "Harry Chapin," TS (Box 31, Folder 42)
    - "The Heart of His Mystery," TS (Box 31, Folder 43)
    - "Here and Now," TS (Box 31, Folder 44)
    - "Heroes In Modern Irish Literature," TS (Box 31, Folder 45)
    - "History," TS (Box 31, Folder 46)
    - "A History of Ireland in Poetry," TS (Box 31, Folder 47)
    - "Horseman Pass By," MS (Box 31, Folder 48)
    - "The Hound of Ulster," TS (Box 31, Folder 49)
    - "The Importance of Poetry," TSS (Box 31, Folder 50)
    - "In Memory of George Buchanan," TSS (Box 31, Folder 51)
    - "The Informed Heart," TS (Box 31, Folder 52)
    - "Introduction to Work in Progress," TSS (Box 31, Folder 53)
    - "Ireland Beats France," [review of Michael Foley's Insomnia in the Afternoon] TS (Box 31, Folder 54)
    - "Ireland's Best?" [review of Paul Durcan's A Snail in My Prime] TSS (Box 31, Folder 55)
    - "Ireland's Greatest Prose Artist," [review of John McGahern's High Ground], TS (Box 31, Folder 56)
    - "Irish Essays on American Writers: Hemingway," TS (Box 31, Folder 57)
    - "Irish Poets on Irish Poetry," TS (Box 31, Folder 58)
    - "Keats," MS (Box 31, Folder 59)
    - "Letter to Dublin," TSS (Box 31, Folder 60)
    - "Letters on Irish Literature," TS (Box 31, Folder 61)
    - "Listening to Singers," TS (Box 31, Folder 62)
    - "Literature in Ireland," TS (Box 31, Folder 63)
    - "Love," TS (Box 31, Folder 64)
    - "The Mainstream of Irish Poetry," TSS (Box 31, Folder 65)
    - "The Man Most Touched," [review of The Wearing of the Black: An Anthology of Contemporary Ulster Poetry, ed. Padraic Fiacc] TS (Box 31, Folder 66)
    - "Manifesto," MS (Box 31, Folder 67)
    - "A Manuel of Revolution," MS (Box 31, Folder 68)
    - "Materialism: The Affluent Society, The Consumer Society," TS (Box 31, Folder 69)
    - "Materialism and the Rise of the Novel," TS (Box 31, Folder 70)
    - "Modern Irish Writers: George Moore," TS (Box 31, Folder 71)
    - "Must Try Harder," [review of The Faber Book of Contemporary Poetry, ed. Paul Muldoon] TS (Box 31, Folder 72)
    - "Nationalism/Internationalism," TS (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - "The New Criticism," TS (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - "A New Primitivism," TS (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - "The New Society" MS (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - "A New View of Literature," TS (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - "No Gunfight at O.K. Corral," [review of Michael Longley's An Exploded View], TSS (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - "Notes Towards Future Residencies," TS (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - "Notes Towards T.S. Eliot," TS (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - "Novelty, Revolution," TS (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - "O'Casey Later Plays," TS (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - "The Oklahoma Element in Brian Friel," TS (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - "Open Letter to an Irish Publisher," TSS (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - "Our Literary Traditions," TS (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - "Parallels in Artistic and Poetic Technique," TS (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - "Philip Larkin," TSS (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - "Piece for Hardin," TSS (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - "Planning, Centralization, Classless Society," TS (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - "The Poetry of Failure," TS (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - "Politics," TS (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - "The Politics of Irish Literature," MS (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - "Pop Songs and Singers," TS (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - "Pope's Ability at Character Portrayal with Some Reference to the Verse Medium," TS (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - "Popular c/f Arden," TS (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - "Popular Music and Democracy and the Influence of the Negro," TS (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - "Pornography," TS (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - "Pornography, Censorship, Obscurity", TSS (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - "Pornography, Religion, Glory," TS (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - "Quality and Relevance," TS (Box 32, Folder 28)
    - "Read Me," TS (Box 32, Folder 29)
    - "The Real Thing Comes Along," [review of Paul Durcan's The Berlin Wall Cafe], TS (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - "The Recipe for all Misfortune, Courage," TS (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - "Reflections on the Poetry of Louis MacNeice," TS (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - "Reform," TSS (Box 32, Folder 33)
    - "Report from the Northwest," TSS (Box 32, Folder 34)
    - "Resignation," TS (Box 32, Folder 35)
    - Review of Jorge Luis Borges's The Aleph and Other Stories, TS (Box 32, Folder 36)
    - Review of Theatre Ulster's production of All My Song, TS (Box 32, Folder 37)
    - Review of the Arts Theatre's production of All Soul's Night, TS (Box 32, Folder 38)
    - Review of Norman Mailer's The Armies of the Night, TS (Box 32, Folder 39)
    - Review of the R.S.C. Belfast Festival's production of The Beaux Stratagem, and Midsummer Nights Dream, TS (Box 32, Folder 40)
    - Review of Liam O'Flaherty's The Black Soul, TS (Box 32, Folder 41)
    - Review of Brecht's Diaries 1920-21 ed. John Willett, TS (Box 32, Folder 42)
    - Review of Seamus Deane's Celtic Revivals: Essays in Modern Irish Literature, TS (Box 32, Folder 43)
    - Review of Sean O'Casey's Cock-a-Doodle Dandy, TS (Box 32, Folder 44)
    - Review of Coleraine Riverside's production of Communication Cord, TS (Box 32, Folder 45)
    - Review of the Ballymena Academy School Players' production of The Crucible, TS (Box 32, Folder 46)
    - Review of the Lyric Theatre's production of Culture Vultures, TS (Box 32, Folder 47)
    - Review of William Trevor's The Day We Got Drunk on Cake, and Mrs. Eckdorf in O'Neill's Hotel, TS (Box 32, Folder 48)
    - Review of Sam Hanna Bell's December Bride, MS and TS (Box 32, Folder 49)
    - Review of Fatal Atrraction, TS (Box 32, Folder 50)
    - Review of The Flying Pickets, TS (Box 32, Folder 51)
    - Review of the Lyric Theatre's production of Footfalls, TS (Box 32, Folder 52)
    - Review of Daniel Corkery's The Hidden Ireland, TS (Box 32, Folder 53)
    - Review of An Irish Jubilee [Irish Traditional Music and Songs sung and Played by Cathal McConnell and Robin Morton] TS (Box 32, Folder 54)
    - Review of Michael Freedland's Irving Berlin, TS (Box 32, Folder 55)
    - Review of Joyce Cary Remembered, ed. Barbara Fisher, TSS (Box 32, Folder 56)
    - Review of the Compass Theatre Company's production of King Lear, TS (Box 32, Folder 57)
    - Review of La Ronde, TS (Box 32, Folder 58)
    - Review of Brian Friel's Making History, TSS (Box 32, Folder 59)
    - Review of the Royal Shakespeare Company's production of A Midsummer Nights Dream, TS (Box 32, Folder 60)
    - Review of the Lyric Theatre's production of Mrs. Warren's Profession, TS (Box 32, Folder 61)
    - Review of the Lyric Theatre's production of Mumbo Jumbo, TS (Box 32, Folder 62)
    - Review of Field Day's production of Pentecost, TS (Box 32, Folder 63)
    - Review of Theatre Ulster's production of The Picture of Dorian Gray, TS (Box 32, Folder 64)
    - Review of Che Guevara's Reminiscences of the Cuban Revolutionary War, TS (Box 32, Folder 65)
    - Review of the Lyric Theatre's production of Romanoff and Juliet, TS (Box 32, Folder 66)
    - Review of Bernard Slade's Same Time Next Year, TS (Box 32, Folder 67)
    - Review of Shorty Rogers's performance at The Guinness Spot, TS (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Review of Seamus Heaney's Station Island, TS (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Review of the Arts Theatre's production of The Stick Wife, TS (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Review of Thomas Kilroy's Tea, Sex, and Shakespeare, TS (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Review of the Ulster Youth Theatre's production of The Tempest, TS (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Review of John Montague's Tidings, TS (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Review of Flann O'Brien's The Third Policeman, TS (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Review of Charles Causely's Underneath the Water, TS (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Review of the Lyric Theatre's production of Waiting for Godot, TS (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Review of the Arts Theatre's production of Welcome to Bladonmore Drive, TS (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Review of James Carrick's With O'Leary in the Grave, TS (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Review of the Arts Theatre's production of The Year of the Hiker, TS (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Review of The Young British Poets, ed. Jeremy Robson, TS (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - "Revolutionary Advice," TSS (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - "Rights," TS (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - "Riots and Literature," TS (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - "Science, Analysis, Machinery," TS (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - "Scroungers or Idealists," TS (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - "Seamus Deane and an Irish Intelligentsia," TS (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - "Security, Insurance, Responsibility, Planning, Philosophy," TS (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - "Setting Yeats to Music," TSS (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - "Sex in Education," TS (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - "Sex, Rectitude, and Loneliness: An Author's Reply," TSS (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - "A Simple Theory of Literature," TSS (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - "Simplicity and Complexity in Poetry," TSS (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - "Singers," TSS (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - "So Won, So Lost," [review of Anthony C. West's As Towns with Fire] TS (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - "Songs," TS (Box 33, Folder 28)
    - "Soyinka and Achebe," TS (Box 33, Folder 29)
    - "Spring Theatre," TSS (Box 33, Folder 30)
    - "The Story of The Honest Ulsterman," TS (Box 33, Folder 31)
    - "Style and Description: Their Significance in Some Irish Novels," TS (Box 33, Folder 32)
    - "T.E. Hulme," TS (Box 33, Folder 33)
    - "Ted Hughes", TS (Box 33, Folder 34)
    - "Tereu: So Rudely Forced," TS (Box 33, Folder 35)
    - "Terence Brown," TS (Box 33, Folder 36)
    - "Theatre," TS (Box 33, Folder 37)
    - "Theatre Ireland," TS (Box 33, Folder 38)
    - "Thoughts for the Day", TSS (Box 33, Folder 39)
    - "The Tradition of Anti-Democracy," TS (Box 33, Folder 40)
    - "The Trouble with Philip Larkin," TSS (Box 33, Folder 41)
    - "The Trouble with Seamus Heaney," TS (Box 33, Folder 42)
    - "Trying to Make Sense of Popular Songs," TS (Box 33, Folder 43)
    - "Two English Poets," [review of Peter Reading's C, and Ukelele Music and John Whitworth's Lovely Day for a Wedding] TSS (Box 33, Folder 44)
    - "2 Hutch," TS (Box 33, Folder 45)
    - "The Unchoked Mainstream," TS [variant title: "Unchoking the Mainstream"] (Box 33, Folder 46)
    - "Uplift and Poetry," TSS (Box 33, Folder 47)
    - "The Use of Criticism," TS (Box 33, Folder 48)
    - "The Use of Popular Songs," TS (Box 33, Folder 49)
    - "Utilitarianism as it Regards Bentham and the Romantic Movement," TS (Box 33, Folder 50)
    - "Violence and Mediocrity," [review of Gerry Adams' Selected Writings], TS (Box 33, Folder 51)
    - "Wole Soyinka," MSS and TSS (Box 33, Folder 52)
    - "Wole Soyinka," TS (Box OP2)
    - "Wordsworth," MS (Box 33, Folder 53)
    - "Worship: A Humanist View," TSS (Box 33, Folder 54)
    - "Yeats Lives," TS (Box 33, Folder 55)
    - "Yeats to Friel," [review of D.E.S. Maxwell's A Critical History of Modern Irish Drama 1891-1980] TS (Box 33, Folder 56)
    - Untitled (Box 33, Folder 57)
    - Short Stories and Novels
    - "The Adventurer," TS (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - "After the Summer School," TS (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - "Benny Carter in Belfast," TSS (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - A Boyhood in the Colony, TSS [1 of 6] (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - A Boyhood in the Colony, MSS and TSS [2 of 6] (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - A Boyhood in the Colony, TSS [3 of 6] (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - A Boyhood in the Colony, TSS [4 of 6] (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - A Boyhood in the Colony, TSS [5 of 6] (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - A Boyhood in the Colony, TSS [6 of 6] (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - "Bradford Days," TS (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - "Ceremonies," MSS and TSS (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - "Christmas," MSS (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - "The Coat Buttons," TS (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - "Cold Morning" TS (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - "A Coleraine Diary," TS (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - "Decent Exposure," TS (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - "Departure," TS (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - "A Depressed Weight Lifter," TS (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - "Derek's Way," MS and TSS (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - "Done," TS (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - "Drink Ritual," TS (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - "Eileen," MS (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - "Eileen Discovers a Sense of Humor," MS (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - "Experiments in Living," TS (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - "Fair Enough," TSS [variant title: "The Living"] (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - "The Father of Men," TSS (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - "First Copulation," TS (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - "The Fly Killer," TS (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - "A Gathering of Eagles," TS (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - "The Great Garvin," TS (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - A Guide to Portrush, TS (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - "Harbour Bar," MS (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - "The Hare," TS (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - "Heaven," TS (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - "Helen," TS (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - "I Dream of Paisley," TSS (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - "I Have Not Been as Others," TS (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - "In the Airport," TS (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - "In the Sun Lounge," TS (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - "In This Weather?," TS (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - "It All Began With a Letter to the President," TS (Box 35, Folder 33)
    - "Johnny," TS (Box 35, Folder 34)
    - "Last Chapter," TS (Box 35, Folder 35)
    - "The Last Day," TS (Box 35, Folder 36)
    - "Leslie St. Clair," TS (Box 35, Folder 37)
    - "Letter for America," TS (Box 35, Folder 38)
    - "Letter from the West," TSS (Box 35, Folder 39)
    - "Letters from London," TS (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - "Letters from an Ulster Bar Man," TS (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - "Letters to a Wife," TSS (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - "Live for Life," TS (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - "The Martyr," MS (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - "Me," TS (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - "Memoirs of a Wedding," TS (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - "Michael's Story," TS (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - "My Father," MS (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - "My Generation/Not My Generation," TS (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - "Nativity," TS (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - "The New New Testament," TS (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - "A New Testament," TS (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - "The Night of the Fire," TSS (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - "Nocturne," TS (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - "Northerners," TS (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - "Not Guilty," TS (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - "A Novella," TS (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - "Old Acquaintance," TS (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - "One of the Crowd," MS (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - "People of the North," TS (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - "The Pink Peignoir," TS (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - "Pound in Coleraine," TSS (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - "Remembrance 1950, Sunday," MS (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - "Romance," TSS (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - "The Short Story," TS (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - "Sir Robert Stephens," TS (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - "So He Chose Action," TS (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - "Something Different," MS (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - "Story for Stand," TS (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - "Suicide," TSS (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - "The Swing Doors of Perception," TS (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - "The Tain," MSS (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - "Take Me Back to Emily," TS (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - "The Teacher," TS (Box 36, Folder 35)
    - "That the Son Should Weep in His Father's Arms," TS (Box 36, Folder 36)
    - "Thoughts for the Day," TSS (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - "To be a Professor of Anglo-Irish," TS (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - "Treasures on Earth," TS (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - "An Ulster Tragedy," TS (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - "Unspeakable Felicity," TS (Box 36, Folder 41)
    - "Ups and Downs of a Protestant Middle Class Folk Singer," TS (Box 36, Folder 42)
    - "The Use of Literature," TS (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - "The War in Derry," TS (Box 36, Folder 44)
    - "A Week Later," MS (Box 36, Folder 45)
    - "West Strand," TS (Box 36, Folder 46)
    - "What 1916 Means to Me," TSS (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - "Where Ever You Are," TSS (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - "The Widow's Tale," TSS (Box 36, Folder 49)
    - "Wife Swapping/Husband Swapping," TSS (Box 36, Folder 50)
    - "Young Frog Face," TSS (Box 36, Folder 51)
    - Untitled (Box 36, Folder 52)
    - Drama
    - Black Eye, MSS and TSS [1 of 2] (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Black Eye, TSS [2 of 2] (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - The Box, TS (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Captain Othello, MSS and TSS (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Captain Othello, TSS (Box OP3)
    - The Cattle Rustling, TSS [1 of 2] (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - The Cattle Rustling, TSS [2 of 2] (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Conversations with a Dumb Waiter, TS (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - The Death of a Gambler, TS (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - A Dialogue for Christmas, TS (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Doilly McCartney's Africa, MSS and TSS [1 of 2] (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Doilly McCartne's Africa, MSS and TSS [2 of 2] (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - A Dove on His Shoulders, TS (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - An Excerise in Dying, TS (Box OP4)
    - Explorations II, TS (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Film Script for David Simmons, TS (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Have You Been to Derry?, MSS and TSS (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Herakles, TS (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Him and the Boys in Love, TS (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - The Hound of Ulster, TS (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - How I Came to Write My Own Songs, TS (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Landmarks, TS (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - The Living Poet-James Simmons, TS (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Love Secrets of Ulster, TS (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - The Lovers of Portrush, MSS and TSS (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Men With Women, TS (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Modern Bard, TS (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Radio Script for the Jubilee Celebrations of the B.B.C., TS (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - The Senator and the Admiral, TS (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Sir George Etherege and Celia, TS (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Songs About Something, TSS (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - The Songs and the Season, TS (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Summer Season and Winter Sports, TS (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - The Tain, TSS (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Tell Us What God Said, TSS (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Those Coleraine Boys, TS (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - The Two Pig Keepers, TS (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - The Way That I Went, TS (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Ulster Portraits, TS (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Ulster Today, TS (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - We're Really Lucky in Ulster, TS (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Why Doesn't Someone Explain?, TSS (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - Untitled (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Lectures
    - "Acting in Lear," MS (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - " The Agamemnon: Aeschylus," TS (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - "Anglo-Irish Introductory Lecture," TS (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - " Antigone," MSS and TS (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - "Arthur Clarke," MS (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - "Arthur Miller," MSS and TSS (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - "A Background to Modern Irish Literature 1939 to the Present Day," TS (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - " Beau Stratagem, George Farquhar," TS (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - "Beckett's Prose," MSS and TSS (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - "Boswell's Life of Johnson," TS (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - "Brecht," MSS and TSS (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - "Brian Moore," MSS and TSS (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - "Brian Moore: The Lonely Passion of Judith Hearne," TS (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - "Cary, Lawrence, Orwell, and Hemingway," TS (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - " Castle Rackrent," TS (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - "Charles Dickens: Hard Times," TS (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - "Charles Dickens: Our Mutual Friend," MS (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - "Chaucer," MS (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - "Chekov," TSS (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - "Contemporary Literature," TS (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - "Criticism," TS (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - " The Crucible," MS and TS (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - "Definitions of Poetry," TS (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - "D.H. Lawrence," MS and TS (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - "D.H. Lawrence and One Aspect of Our Dissatisfaction with Modern Society," TS (Box 40, Folder 25)
    - "D.H. Lawrence: Enemies of Democracy," TS (Box 40, Folder 26)
    - "Elements of Drama," TSS (Box 40, Folder 27)
    - "Enlightened Villains," TS (Box 40, Folder 28)
    - " The Entertainer: John Osborne," TS (Box 40, Folder 29)
    - "The Epic," TS (Box 40, Folder 30)
    - "Ernest Hemingway: A Clean, Well-Lighted Place," MS (Box 40, Folder 31)
    - "Ernest Hemingway: The Sublime in Contemporary Life," TS (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - " The Father: Strindberg," TS (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - "Fielding's Joseph Andrews," TS (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - "Forrest Reid," TSS (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - "Francis Stuart, Memorial," TS (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - "Frank O'Connor," MSS and TSS (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - "George Bernard Shaw," MSS (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - "George Moore," MS (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - "Gerard Manley Hopkins," TSS (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - " Hamlet," TS (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - "T he Heart of Darkness," MS (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - "Heroic Epic," MS and TS (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - "History and Philosophy of Literature," MSS and TSS (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - " The Homecoming: Harold Pinter," MSS and TSS (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - "Ibsen," MSS and TSS (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - "Imperialism in Literature: Anglo/Irish Literature," TS (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - "Irish Literature," TS (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - "The Irish Short Story," MSS and TSS (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - "James Stephens," TS (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - "Jealousy," TS (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - "John Montague," TS (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - "John Morrow: The Confessions of Pronsias O'Toole," MS and TS (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - "Joseph Conrad," MS (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - "Joyce Cary in Ireland," TSS (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - "Joyce: Dubliners and Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man," MSS and TSS (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - "Leavis," MS (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - "Lecture on English Love Poetry," TS (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - "The Literary Achievement of George Russell," MSS and TSS (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - " Lord Jim," TS (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - "Louis MacNeice," TS (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - " Major Barbara," MS (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - "Mary Levin," TS (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - "Milton," MS (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - "Modern Drama," MSS and TSS (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - "Modern Irish Writing, Poetry, A Northern Perspective," TS (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - "More Notes and Queries on the Study of English Literature," TSS (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - "The Nature and Importance of Literature," TS (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - "Old English," MSS (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - "Orwell on Dickens," TS (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - " Othello," TS (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - " Passage to India," MS (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - "Patrick Boyle: Like Any Other Man," TS (Box 42, Folder 20)